<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gregg Claycamp</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Gregg Claycamp</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu10226378635250344412.png</url>
      <title>Gregg Claycamp</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/event/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/event/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchmey&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Shortcodes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/mynext/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 20:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/mynext/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here’s a new slide </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/slides/heres-a-new-slide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 20:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/slides/heres-a-new-slide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;slide 1
—-
Slide 2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining Objectives for Team Decisions</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/defining-the-objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/defining-the-objectives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;font size= 4rem&gt; 
&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;This is a demo book chapter: it will be deleted when the eBook (in progress) is posted.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-introduction&#34;&gt;1 Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is about the need for working groups and teams to define their decision objectives for decisions important to accomplishing the group’s goals. Important decisions are typically complex, having multiple objectives that both identify the important reasons for the decision and also provide a framework for defining criteria that can be used to choose among two or many alternatives. The process of multicriteria decision making (MCDM) is well suited for finding an objective solution for complex decisions. Although the first step in most MCDM or MCDA processes is to clearly define the overall objective that the decision maker or decision making group wishes to accomplish, it is often a neglected or poorly executed. In this post, I discuss decision making objectives and how they fit into various MCDM processes. I describe describe some signs and symptoms of a weak MCDM process due to poor attention to structured thinking about objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;11-clear-decision-objectives-are-essential&#34;&gt;1.1 Clear Decision Objectives are Essential&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes weeks or months into a team’s decision making process, debate arises around the meaning of the decision objective(s) possibly stalling the team’s progress. Different perceptions among the team about purpose of the decision creates uncertainty, a poorly formed decision and might even lead to a dysfunctional team process. The team’s growing uncertainty often leads to a request that the decision owner restate her objective(s) to the working group. In other situations, the decision making team might complete their decision-making charge recommendation under a shared misunderstanding of the objectives only to be told that from the decision owner’s perspective, the team answered the &lt;em&gt;wrong question&lt;/em&gt;! If broken decision making processes occur fre&lt;em&gt;quently in the organization, there will be a growing list of reluctant volunteers for&lt;/em&gt; ad hoc* decision making groups. Ultimately, poor processes affect organizational performance and resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The achievement of objectives is the sole reason for being interested in any decision. (Keeney 1992, 55).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeney’s succinct statement or similar statements appear frequently over decades of MCDM research. Yet I believe that most decision facilitators or coaches will attest to the notion that poorly-stated objectives remains a common problem for both individual or team decision making. The decision objective(s)–i.e., &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;reason(s) for the decision&lt;/em&gt;—are sometimes poorly articulated even for critical strategic decisions. In the absence of clear objectives, the MCDM process fails often leads to disillusionment and frustration with formal decision making when it is most needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;12-doesnt-everyone-already-know-the-objectives&#34;&gt;1.2 Doesn’t everyone already know the objectives?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about your experience working in groups or teams who have been charged with finding solutions to complex problems, such as developing new information or prioritizing among projects in the organization’s tactical plan. Did the team discuss and articulate the main objective, or was the objective simply “handed down” from the decision owner? Senior management or next-level managers likely pass the team’s decision-making charge and expectations either verbally in the form of a committee charge or problem statement. The decision objective(s) might be well understood and part of both the culture and business process in most routine decisions. But novel and complex decision settings can lead to both nuanced and vague decision objectives for a variety of reasons, such as the uncertainty about a novel situation or even a concern by management for appearing to dictate a decision process. These are the team decision making situations that we are most interested in understanding and improving, so-called “Category II” decisions that are “nonroutine, nonrecurring and uncertain of outcome”(Harrison 1999). The remainder of this essay focuses on the importance of setting clear objectives for these difficult multiobjective decisions. A clear articulation of the objectives and a communication processes keeping the interpretation timely is crucial to an efficient decision-making process and achieving a lasting and satisfying choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MCDM tools are not for the routine, “no-brainer” decisions for which the objectives, alternatives and consequences are well understood. But for all other decisions, clearly thought about and well-articulated objectives are a crucial for beginning the decision-making process on a good footing. The remainder of this essay explores team-based identification and structuring of objectives for several kinds of decision situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-decision-objectives&#34;&gt;2 Decision Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stating or identifying the reason for the decision–the objectives–is often the first step in MCDM models ((Communities (UK) and Government 2009; Keeney 1992; Belton and Stewart 2002); others) and individual decision making guides (e.g., (Hammond, Keeney, and Raiffa 2002)). A generalized process for MCDM using multicriteria decision analysis (MCDA) is given here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify and clearly define objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify alternatives for achieving the objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify the criteria and attributes to be used to compare the alternatives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze the alternatives and uncertainties: (“modeling” the decision)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make choice or prioritize options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examine results and establish a follow-up period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This general procedure has been slightly adapted for risk-focused prioritization used in projects I either led or facilitated at FDA and NIH (Fig. 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/Risk-Focused-Prioritization.png&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;/&gt; &lt;font size=2em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Fig. 1. Risk-Focused Prioritization Process.&lt;/strong&gt; An example MCDA process in which the identification and statement of the objectives is the first important step.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most MCDM scholars and practitioners describe an objectives identification and statement process (Keeney 1992, 2012; Harrison 1999; Saaty and Peniwati 2013); however, the term “objectives” might not be used either explicitly or in a definition. For example, Belton and Stewart subsume objectives identification within the process of “problem structuring” (Belton and Stewart 2002). Harrison refers to “managerial objectives” implying that objectives are specified in an organizational top-down manner (Harrison 1999).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, both individuals and organizations have some notion of &lt;strong&gt;strategic objectives&lt;/strong&gt; as guides to the individual’s or organization’s decision making from a very general, high-level perspective. For individuals, these might be expressed as “life goals,” while organizations might blend strategic objectives with mission statements. In either case, strategic objectives might not even be written individually or organizationally as an objective. Even if objectives are formalized, the strategic objective level may be too general to guide decision making in any specific situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeney writes from the perspective of decision sciences and decision-making situations ranging from the personal (Hammond, Keeney, and Raiffa 2002) to the organizational and societal (Keeney 1992, 2004). Keeney parses objectives into strategic, fundamental and means-ends objectives (Keeney 1992).&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fundamental objectives&lt;/strong&gt; are the decision-making goals in a narrower context. “A fundamental objective characterizes an essential reason for interest in the decision situation.” (Keeney 1992, 34). In contrast, Keeney’s &lt;strong&gt;means-ends objectives&lt;/strong&gt; state the ways in which the goals might be achieved. For example, the fundamental objective of “increase supplier audits by 10%” could have an underlying means-end objectives of “hire more auditing staff” and “contract more third-party auditors.” These “actionable” objectives are means to support the ends of increasing audits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The management, economics and psychology literature have also contributed much research and theory about how decisions are made (e.g., Harrison 1999). Decision theorists in these disciplines often do not call out the development of strategic and fundamental objectives as a process step, rather, they tend to assume that “management objectives” set the context for the decision (e.g., Harrison 1999). Nevertheless, the business management perspective on the importance of setting objectives before attempting decision making (in a vacuum) is clear. For example, in 1964 Granger stated that the management literature was by then “teeming” with articles on the theory on setting and measuring the objectives (Granger 1964). Also, the importance of objectives is nicely stated by Harrison:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives, which underlie the effective management of any type of formal organization, are not abstractions. They are the commitments to action through which the mission of the organization is carried out, and they are the standards against which the performance of management is measured. (Harrison 1999, 43)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harrison’s statement is suited to the idea of strategic objectives. Identifying fundamental objectives for the decision situation makes the general objective specific and “real” for the team of decision makers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/img/ObjectivesandLocus.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fig. 1. A view of the dominant responsibility for objectives/decisions process.&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;/&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;3&#34; line-height=15px /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fig. 1. A view of the dominant responsibility for objectives/decisions process.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, the organization “owns” the overall strategic objectives and typically embeds them in a strategic plan. Fundamental objectives definition is done for important decisions and might be identified and developed at a division or team level. Fundamental objectives apply to a defined decision situation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;font size=&#34;4&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;22-means-ends-objectives-anticipate-a-solution&#34;&gt;2.2 Means-ends objectives anticipate a solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are decision situations designed to update a decision or prioritization model with new information, criteria or re-scaled judgments and for which the fundamental objectives are well-established and understood by the decision making team. Such is frequently the case in a regulatory environment where the fundamental objective exists within a specific regulation or standard. The discussion about and definition of means-ends objectives helps the decision team focus on how the fundamental objectives are or might be achieved using new ideas, data and procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly, it is possible to charge a working group with solving means-ends objectives-focused problem. But, if the group does not articulate the connections among the means-ends objectives with the overarching fundamental objectives, the decision will not likely be as robust as it could be otherwise. Often, the urge to produce “tangible results” for an organization shifts the team’s focus to defining means-ends objectives before clearly defining the fundamental objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-decision-making-by-teams&#34;&gt;3 Decision making by teams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important decision-making, whether at the board, managerial, or operational level, typically involves groups of decision makers. There might be several groups of experts who have input, information gathering and evaluation tasks and the groups sometimes includes stakeholder roles in the decision (Harrison 1999). I will generalize “team” to mean the decision making group who a charged with working through a process for either a one-off choice, a prioritization of alternatives within a portfolio, or performing reviews of ongoing decision making functions. Teams might be standing or &lt;em&gt;ad hoc&lt;/em&gt; working groups or function teams within the organizational hierarchy. Examples of team decision making are very diverse including decisions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;within strategic planning;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prioritizing a list of leadership candidates;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choosing supplier(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choosing new site(s) or market(s);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;initiating a quality risk management process;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;initiating a new failure modes and effects analysis (FMEA), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prioritizing risk management resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on a team’s function, their decision-making process can be thought of as either strategic or tactical. Although strategic decisions might follow a formalized decision making process including a facilitator, tactical decisions, such as “choose a new supplier,” are likely rely on informal team decision making. In other instances, a tactical team might be charged by a manager with advising management on choosing a new site or even allocating resources for risk and quality management activities. Such decisions benefit from–if not &lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt;–a more formal decision making process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;31-decision-making-team-composition&#34;&gt;3.1 Decision-Making Team composition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams are comprised of individuals who are more likely than not to have a differing perspectives on the problem at hand. Although increasing the team size for diversity of experience, knowledge, disciplines and skills among members can improve the generation of decision objectives and alternatives, it comes at a cost of decreasing individual participation in the exercise (Chapman 1998). Describing individual preferences for how objective and subjective inputs factor into a final choice–given uncertainties–is the subject of classical decision analysis. But classical decision analysis is difficult to extend to many decision makers. As Keeney outlined across multiple publications, some theons for inherent complexity in team decision-making include (Keeney 2004, 2012):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team members view their common decision differently;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the team agrees on the alternatives and consequences, the members may assign different chances to events;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consensus or similar shared decision policies mean that team member’s perspectives of the decision and evaluation of the alternatives must be incorporated in the overall decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other authors discuss how organizational politics, individual job-related agendas, the levels of individual knowledge and social psychology can challenge group decision-making (Harrison 1999; Belton and Stewart 2002; Saaty and Peniwati 2013)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, useful concepts from decision analysis inform analogous processes in team-based MCDM. This is supported by a significant body of empirical reports on “what works” in group decision making. Finally, the applicability of methods, such as MCDA, to group decision making has fueled a nearly exponential growth in tools and applications since the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complex decisions have both objective and subjective inputs, sometimes many alternatives and conflicting attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;32-more-data-for-decision-making&#34;&gt;3.2 More data for decision making?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern organizations have remarkable access to data and knowledge management tools which can be used to inform both strategic and tactical decisions including the allocation of resources to address risk. Although data and knowledge management contribute to reducing uncertainty in decision making, they neither define nor eliminate uncertainties and risks impacting the achievement of a desired objectives. multicriteria decision analysis (MCDA) has evolved as a structured way to define decision objectives and combine the various inputs into objectively quantifying the decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is paradoxical that greater accessibility to data and information can both complicate and improve team decision making. A few keystrokes in a contemporary internet search can lead to hundreds of pages of data and information about buying cars. Although the volume of information can be daunting, in fact, thoughtful analysis of the information likely improves the quality of decision making by reducing uncertainty. The volumes and different types of information make MCDM challenging enough for a single decision-maker; and, adding multiple decision makers to the process only amplifies the complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proponents of multicriteria decision analysis argue that many of the challenges within group decision making can be overcome by following processes that have their roots in applied decision analysis, such as the ProACT procedures (Hammond, Keeney, and Raiffa 2002) and value-focused thinking (Keeney 1992) discussed in the following paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many “how-to” books in the trade and peer-review literature discussing individual decision making. One of the most useful and accessible books is &lt;em&gt;Smart Choices&lt;/em&gt; (Hammond, Keeney, and Raiffa 2002). The book is an excellent introduction to decision making with multiple criteria. The authors recommended a “ProACT/URL” process for these difficult decisions as described in the following table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pr&lt;/strong&gt;oblem&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Work on the right decision problem&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O&lt;/strong&gt;bjective&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Specify your objectives&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;lternatives&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Create Imaginative alternatives&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;onsequences&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Understand the consequences&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;rade-offs&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Grapple with your trade-offs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Uncertainty&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Clarify your uncertainties&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Risk tolerance&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Think hard about your risk tolerance&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Linked decisions&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Consider linked decisions&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table 1. The PrOACT/URL approach to decision making by (Hammond, Keeney, and Raiffa 2002).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less complex decisions might be accomplished following only the &lt;strong&gt;PrOACT&lt;/strong&gt; process while more complex decisions include assessing uncertainties, risk tolerance of the decision maker and whether or not the decision is linked to other decisions. Adding these features is the source of the complete acronym, “ProACT/URL.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-understanding-the-objectives&#34;&gt;4 Understanding the Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/img/stratplanning-post-it.jpg&#34; data-position=&#34;center&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;/&gt; &lt;font size=&#34;3&#34; &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fig.3 A common method for objectives identification is the “Post-It” method.&lt;/strong&gt;(Photo by Daria Nepriakhina on Unsplash.com)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fundamental objectives of the decision capture the reason(s) we are deciding choosing among two or more alternatives (–sometimes known as choices; options). The fundamental objectives are no less important to a decision than are clearly stated and testable hypotheses to a high-quality research design. Even decisions in our personal lives have objectives that a perceived differently by individuals. For example, how many ways might an objective, “achieve personal satisfaction in my career,” be perceived and defined among even a small number of individuals?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-pressure-to-produce-tangible-results&#34;&gt;5 Pressure to Produce Tangible Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-structured-approaches&#34;&gt;6 Structured Approaches?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Keeney wrote the paragraph (above) in 1992, he was correct in noting the lack of structured approaches for thinking critically through multicriteria decisions. Two decades later, we have witnessed an exponential growth in research and application of multicriteria decision analysis (MCDA) of which Keeney’s “value-focused thinking” is one of the “best practices.” There are numerous examples of MCDA from the government and industry health care that translate efficiently to processes accessible to scientists and clinicians. The structured approaches are now available, and all that remains is the will to implement them. The will to implement MCDA will come from the realization that decision making is an acquired skill based on fundamental decision theory and practice. Better decisions come from practicing the learned skills. (Keeney 2004).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAVED: Keeney ((Keeney 2004)) offers several explanations for this predicament, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decision makers do not understand their objectives well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decision makers are routinely under time pressure to produce tangible results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lack of structured approaches to promote systematic and deep thinking about objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTES—————— (Ley-Borrás 2015) in Abstract p.) States that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, the decision situation is typically not explicitly selected, or even well defined, which easily leads to deciding about treating symptoms instead of underlying causes; to deciding with a narrow scope that misses important elements; and, in general, to missing the opportunity of analyzing valuable alternative decision situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, it is common that specific decision situation are not selected.p46&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuals and decision teams tend to react to problems and opportunities by searching for a “solution” without questioning the initial perception or formulation of the decision situation. This easily leads to deciding about visible consequences instead of underlying causes; to deciding with a narrow scope that misses important elements;to deciding on an overly broad issue causing important elements to not receive proper attention for lack of time or resources; to deciding on an issue attending only to short-term effects when long-term results are very important; and, in general, to missing the opportunity of analyzing valuable alternative decision situations. p. 46&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should come as no surprise that a group of experts who are diverse in their training and experience perceive stated objectives differently. For nearly a century psychologists, decision scientists and economists have studied the inevitable intrusion of our subjective, perceiving minds into what is optimistically believed to be an objective decision making process (Kahneman 2011; Sunstein et al. 2002; Ariely 2009; Kahneman, Slovic, and Tversky 1982). Internal processing of decision objectives is so individualized that individuals have trouble analyzing other perceptions among the the group. After a career’s worth of troubleshooting complex decisions and scholarship in decision analysis, Ralph Keeney recently recommend that groups not work through objectives and preference together until group members have defined the problem individually (Keeney 2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTES———-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#refs .references .csl-bib-body .hanging-indent}
::: {#ref-Ariely2009 .csl-entry}
Ariely, Dan. 2009. &lt;em&gt;Predictably Irrational&lt;/em&gt;. Harper-Collins eBooks.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Belton2002 .csl-entry}
Belton, V, and T. J. Stewart. 2002. &lt;em&gt;Multiple Criteria Decision Analysis, an Integrated Approach&lt;/em&gt;. Kluware Academic Publishers.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Chapman-RJ1998 .csl-entry}
Chapman, R. J. 1998. “[The effectiveness of working group risk identification and assessment techniques]{.nocase}.” &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 13 (6): 333–43.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-UKCommunities2009 .csl-entry}
Communities (UK), Department for, and Local Government. 2009. “Multi-Criteria Analysis: A Manual.” &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/7612/1132618.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/7612/1132618.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Granger1964 .csl-entry}
Granger, Charles H. 1964. “The Hierarchy of Objectives.” &lt;em&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/em&gt;.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Hammond2002 .csl-entry}
Hammond, J S, R L Keeney, and H Raiffa. 2002. [&lt;em&gt;Smart Choices. A Practical Guide to Making Better Decisions&lt;/em&gt;]{.nocase}. Book. Paperback; New York: Broadway Books.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Harrison1999 .csl-entry}
Harrison, E. Frank. 1999. &lt;em&gt;The Managerial Decision-Making Process&lt;/em&gt;. Fifth. Houghton-Mifflin.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Kahneman2011 .csl-entry}
Kahneman, D. 2011. &lt;em&gt;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/em&gt;. Farrar, Straus; Giroux.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Kahneman1982 .csl-entry}
Kahneman, D, P Slovic, and A Tversky. 1982. &lt;em&gt;Judgments Under Uncertainty: Heuristics and Biases&lt;/em&gt;. Cambridge University Press.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Keeney1992 .csl-entry}
Keeney, R L. 1992. &lt;em&gt;Value-Focused Thinking&lt;/em&gt;. Book. Cambridge University Press.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Keeney2004 .csl-entry}
———. 2004. “[Making better decision makers]{.nocase}.” Journal Article. &lt;em&gt;Decision Analysis&lt;/em&gt; 1 (4): 193–204.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Keeney2012 .csl-entry}
———. 2012. “[Value-focused brainstorming]{.nocase}.” Journal Article. &lt;em&gt;Decision Analysis&lt;/em&gt; 9 (4): 303–13.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Keeney2013 .csl-entry}
———. 2013. “Foundations for Group Decision Analysis.” &lt;em&gt;Decision Analysis&lt;/em&gt; 10: 103–20.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Ley-Borras2015 .csl-entry}
Ley-Borrás, Roberto. 2015. “Deciding on the Decision Situation to Analyze: The Critical First Step of a Decision Analysis.” &lt;em&gt;Decision Analysis&lt;/em&gt; 12 (March). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1287/deca.2014.0308&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1287/deca.2014.0308&lt;/a&gt;.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Saaty2013 .csl-entry}
Saaty, T L, and K Peniwati. 2013. &lt;em&gt;Group Decision Making: Drawing Out and Reconciling Differences&lt;/em&gt;. 2013; 2008. RWS Publications.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#ref-Sunstein2002 .csl-entry}
Sunstein, Cass R, Daniel Kahneman, David Schkade, and Ilana Ritov. 2002. “Predictably Incoherent Judgments.” &lt;em&gt;Stanford Law Review&lt;/em&gt; 54: 1153–1215.
:::
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe this approach is useful in many team decision making settings, although the relative importance of objectives in a hierarchy differs somewhat from the business literature.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few Lessons from Facilitating or Leading Risk-Based Decision-Making</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2023-facilitating-rbdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2023-facilitating-rbdm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- 




  
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; --&gt;
&lt;!-- Add the publication&#39;s **full text** or **supplementary notes** here. You can use rich formatting such as including [code, math, and images](https://docs.hugoblox.com/content/writing-markdown-latex/). --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claycamp, H Gregg (2023) &amp;ldquo;A Few Lessons from Facilitating or Leading Risk-Based Decision-Making,&amp;rdquo;
Level 3: Vol. 19: Iss. 1, Article 4.
doi:https://doi.org/10.21427/qgmj-vv95
Available at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arrow.tudublin.ie/level3/vol19/iss1/4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://arrow.tudublin.ie/level3/vol19/iss1/4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/experience/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn JavaScript</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching/js/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching/js/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hugoblox.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo Blox Builder&lt;/a&gt; is designed to give technical content creators a seamless experience. You can focus on the content and the Hugo Blox Builder which this template is built upon handles the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed videos, podcasts, code, LaTeX math, and even test students!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this page, you&amp;rsquo;ll find some examples of the types of technical content that can be rendered with Hugo Blox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teach your course by sharing videos with your students. Choose from one of the following approaches:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D2vj0WcvH5c?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; youtube w7Ft2ymGmfc &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bilibili&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; bilibili id=&amp;quot;BV1WV4y1r7DF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos may be added to a page by either placing them in your &lt;code&gt;assets/media/&lt;/code&gt; media library or in your &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/page-bundles/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&amp;rsquo;s folder&lt;/a&gt;, and then embedding them with the &lt;em&gt;video&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; video src=&amp;quot;my_video.mp4&amp;quot; controls=&amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add a podcast or music to a page by placing the MP3 file in the page&amp;rsquo;s folder or the media library folder and then embedding the audio on your page with the &lt;em&gt;audio&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; audio src=&amp;quot;ambient-piano.mp3&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try it out:&lt;/p&gt;








  








&lt;audio controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;//localhost:1313/teaching/js/ambient-piano.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-students&#34;&gt;Test students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide a simple yet fun self-assessment by revealing the solutions to challenges with the &lt;code&gt;spoiler&lt;/code&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;spoiler&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;👉 Click to view the solution&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;You found me!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;spoiler&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;cursor-pointer&#34;&gt;👉 Click to view the solution&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;rounded-lg bg-neutral-50 dark:bg-neutral-800 p-2&#34;&gt;
    You found me 🎉
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder supports a Markdown extension for $\LaTeX$ math. You can enable this feature by toggling the &lt;code&gt;math&lt;/code&gt; option in your &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To render &lt;em&gt;inline&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;block&lt;/em&gt; math, wrap your LaTeX math with &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$...${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$$...$${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;We wrap the LaTeX math in the Hugo Blox &lt;em&gt;math&lt;/em&gt; shortcode to prevent Hugo rendering our math as Markdown.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;math block&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\gamma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\frac&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^T &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; |}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;

$$\gamma_{n} = \frac{ \left | \left (\mathbf x_{n} - \mathbf x_{n-1} \right )^T \left [\nabla F (\mathbf x_{n}) - \nabla F (\mathbf x_{n-1}) \right ] \right |}{\left \|\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n}) - \nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n-1}) \right \|^2}$$


&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;inline math&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; renders as $\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})$
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;multi-line math&lt;/strong&gt; using the math linebreak (&lt;code&gt;\\&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;k;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\begin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;


$$
f(k;p_{0}^{*}) = \begin{cases}p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=1, \\
1-p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=0.\end{cases}
$$



&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder utilises Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Markdown extension for highlighting code syntax. The code theme can be selected in the &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```python
import pandas as pd
data = pd.read_csv(&amp;quot;data.csv&amp;quot;)
data.head()
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pandas&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;read_csv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;data.csv&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;inline-images&#34;&gt;Inline Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34; data-lang=&#34;go&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;icon&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;python&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;}}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;inline-block  pr-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;svg style=&#34;height: 1em; transform: translateY(0.1em);&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; height=&#34;1em&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 448 512&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M439.8 200.5c-7.7-30.9-22.3-54.2-53.4-54.2h-40.1v47.4c0 36.8-31.2 67.8-66.8 67.8H172.7c-29.2 0-53.4 25-53.4 54.3v101.8c0 29 25.2 46 53.4 54.3 33.8 9.9 66.3 11.7 106.8 0 26.9-7.8 53.4-23.5 53.4-54.3v-40.7H226.2v-13.6h160.2c31.1 0 42.6-21.7 53.4-54.2 11.2-33.5 10.7-65.7 0-108.6zM286.2 404c11.1 0 20.1 9.1 20.1 20.3 0 11.3-9 20.4-20.1 20.4-11 0-20.1-9.2-20.1-20.4.1-11.3 9.1-20.3 20.1-20.3zM167.8 248.1h106.8c29.7 0 53.4-24.5 53.4-54.3V91.9c0-29-24.4-50.7-53.4-55.6-35.8-5.9-74.7-5.6-106.8.1-45.2 8-53.4 24.7-53.4 55.6v40.7h106.9v13.6h-147c-31.1 0-58.3 18.7-66.8 54.2-9.8 40.7-10.2 66.1 0 108.6 7.6 31.6 25.7 54.2 56.8 54.2H101v-48.8c0-35.3 30.5-66.4 66.8-66.4zm-6.7-142.6c-11.1 0-20.1-9.1-20.1-20.3.1-11.3 9-20.4 20.1-20.4 11 0 20.1 9.2 20.1 20.4s-9 20.3-20.1 20.3z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt; Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-helpful-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page helpful? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Python</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching/python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hugoblox.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo Blox Builder&lt;/a&gt; is designed to give technical content creators a seamless experience. You can focus on the content and the Hugo Blox Builder which this template is built upon handles the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed videos, podcasts, code, LaTeX math, and even test students!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this page, you&amp;rsquo;ll find some examples of the types of technical content that can be rendered with Hugo Blox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teach your course by sharing videos with your students. Choose from one of the following approaches:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D2vj0WcvH5c?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; youtube w7Ft2ymGmfc &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bilibili&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; bilibili id=&amp;quot;BV1WV4y1r7DF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos may be added to a page by either placing them in your &lt;code&gt;assets/media/&lt;/code&gt; media library or in your &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/page-bundles/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&amp;rsquo;s folder&lt;/a&gt;, and then embedding them with the &lt;em&gt;video&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; video src=&amp;quot;my_video.mp4&amp;quot; controls=&amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add a podcast or music to a page by placing the MP3 file in the page&amp;rsquo;s folder or the media library folder and then embedding the audio on your page with the &lt;em&gt;audio&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; audio src=&amp;quot;ambient-piano.mp3&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try it out:&lt;/p&gt;








  








&lt;audio controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;//localhost:1313/teaching/python/ambient-piano.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-students&#34;&gt;Test students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide a simple yet fun self-assessment by revealing the solutions to challenges with the &lt;code&gt;spoiler&lt;/code&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;spoiler&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;👉 Click to view the solution&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;You found me!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;spoiler&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;cursor-pointer&#34;&gt;👉 Click to view the solution&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;rounded-lg bg-neutral-50 dark:bg-neutral-800 p-2&#34;&gt;
    You found me 🎉
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder supports a Markdown extension for $\LaTeX$ math. You can enable this feature by toggling the &lt;code&gt;math&lt;/code&gt; option in your &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To render &lt;em&gt;inline&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;block&lt;/em&gt; math, wrap your LaTeX math with &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$...${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$$...$${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;We wrap the LaTeX math in the Hugo Blox &lt;em&gt;math&lt;/em&gt; shortcode to prevent Hugo rendering our math as Markdown.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;math block&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\gamma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\frac&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^T &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; |}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;

$$\gamma_{n} = \frac{ \left | \left (\mathbf x_{n} - \mathbf x_{n-1} \right )^T \left [\nabla F (\mathbf x_{n}) - \nabla F (\mathbf x_{n-1}) \right ] \right |}{\left \|\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n}) - \nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n-1}) \right \|^2}$$


&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;inline math&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; renders as $\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})$
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;multi-line math&lt;/strong&gt; using the math linebreak (&lt;code&gt;\\&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;k;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\begin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;


$$
f(k;p_{0}^{*}) = \begin{cases}p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=1, \\
1-p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=0.\end{cases}
$$



&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder utilises Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Markdown extension for highlighting code syntax. The code theme can be selected in the &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```python
import pandas as pd
data = pd.read_csv(&amp;quot;data.csv&amp;quot;)
data.head()
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pandas&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;read_csv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;data.csv&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;inline-images&#34;&gt;Inline Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34; data-lang=&#34;go&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;icon&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;python&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;}}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;inline-block  pr-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;svg style=&#34;height: 1em; transform: translateY(0.1em);&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; height=&#34;1em&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 448 512&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M439.8 200.5c-7.7-30.9-22.3-54.2-53.4-54.2h-40.1v47.4c0 36.8-31.2 67.8-66.8 67.8H172.7c-29.2 0-53.4 25-53.4 54.3v101.8c0 29 25.2 46 53.4 54.3 33.8 9.9 66.3 11.7 106.8 0 26.9-7.8 53.4-23.5 53.4-54.3v-40.7H226.2v-13.6h160.2c31.1 0 42.6-21.7 53.4-54.2 11.2-33.5 10.7-65.7 0-108.6zM286.2 404c11.1 0 20.1 9.1 20.1 20.3 0 11.3-9 20.4-20.1 20.4-11 0-20.1-9.2-20.1-20.4.1-11.3 9.1-20.3 20.1-20.3zM167.8 248.1h106.8c29.7 0 53.4-24.5 53.4-54.3V91.9c0-29-24.4-50.7-53.4-55.6-35.8-5.9-74.7-5.6-106.8.1-45.2 8-53.4 24.7-53.4 55.6v40.7h106.9v13.6h-147c-31.1 0-58.3 18.7-66.8 54.2-9.8 40.7-10.2 66.1 0 108.6 7.6 31.6 25.7 54.2 56.8 54.2H101v-48.8c0-35.3 30.5-66.4 66.8-66.4zm-6.7-142.6c-11.1 0-20.1-9.1-20.1-20.3.1-11.3 9-20.4 20.1-20.4 11 0 20.1 9.2 20.1 20.4s-9 20.3-20.1 20.3z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt; Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-helpful-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page helpful? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 is Not Just Like the Annual Flu</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/covid-not-flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/covid-not-flu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the six months of the coronavirus pandemic in the US, I have had many casual conversations with strangers or family in which the individual suggests that &amp;ldquo;COVID-19 is just like an annual flu.&amp;rdquo; This notion is far from the truth even in the face of a general similarity that they are both respiratory infections. In this post I compare quantitative features of
COVID-19 with H1N1 and other flu-like illnesses, Ebola virus disease (EVD), and SARS to show differences between COVID-19 and the flu. Of course, this is not the first time these comparisons have been made in public media; rather, this post is only my perspective on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several ways in which the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic and some recent other pandemics can be compared. Sometimes, the endpoints for comparing the pandemic are cherry-picked to support the individual&amp;rsquo;s or organization&amp;rsquo;s purpose. But generally speaking, quantitative comparisons of pandemics begin using fundamental measures, such as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the number of cases,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the number of deaths, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the population size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although these pandemic measures start with the seemingly simple process of counting cases and deaths, the luxury of that simplicity is seldom achievable. Each numerical comparison is nuanced and sometimes even specific to &lt;em&gt;which&lt;/em&gt; outbreak of complex disease. The field of epidemiology&amp;ndash;the study of diseases in populations&amp;ndash;uses these fundamental measures to derive more specific measures of incidence, prevalence, and risk (Below). Trained infectious disease scientists and clinicians seldom made casual comparisons using only the above terms, but instead, carefully state the  assumptions and possibly caveats necessary to make scientifically valid comparisons using an array of terms. For this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll assume that such simplifying assumptions and caveats could be easily resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparing-the-number-of-cases&#34;&gt;Comparing the number of cases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of cases (&amp;ldquo;case counts&amp;rdquo;) is a basic measure used to routinely monitor diseases in addition to detecting an emerging epidemic disease.^[Both chronic and infectious diseases are counted on a regular basis as part of public health risk management. The CDC website has a good explanation of surveillance: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/chronicdisease/data/surveillance.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CDC Surveillance&lt;/a&gt;] The following figure (Fig.1) shows the worldwide case counts for the past SARS, EVD and H1N1 (Swine Flu) outbreaks and the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic. Note that the horizontal axis is a logarithmic scale, e.g., moving in powers of 10 (10, 100, 1000, 10000, &amp;hellip;). If not shown that way, the tens of millions of cases in COVID-19 and H1N1 would visually swamp the &lt;em&gt;thousands-fold&lt;/em&gt; fewer cases of Ebola and SARS. (You would need a very wide monitor to display the graph!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- ```
{r opts, include=TRUE, echo=FALSE}
#knitr::opts_chunk$set(&#34;fig.path&#34;= &#34;/post/2020-08-18-covid-19-is-still-not-the-annual-flu.en_files/figure-html/&#34;)
``` --&gt;
&lt;!-- ```
{r plotbarcase, include=TRUE, echo=FALSE}
library(ggplot2)

cases &lt;- c(74210337,60800000,28646,8096)

outbreak &lt;- c(&#34;COVID-19 (2019)&#34;, &#34;H1N1 (2009)&#34;, &#34;Ebola (2014)&#34;, &#34;SARS (2003)&#34;)

df &lt;- as.data.frame(cases, outbreak)
theme_set(theme_minimal())

# Plot
g &lt;- ggplot(df, aes(x = reorder(outbreak, cases), cases))
g + geom_bar(stat=&#34;identity&#34;, width = 0.7, fill=&#34;blue&#34;) + 
   geom_text(aes(label=cases), hjust=1.6, color=&#34;white&#34;, size=4.0) +
      labs(title=&#34;Fig.1: Worldwide Case Counts in Major Outbreaks&#34;, 
           caption=&#34;Data sources: WHO, CDC&#34;) +
      theme(axis.title.y=element_blank() ) + 
      theme(axis.text.y = element_text(size=rel(1.5))) +
 scale_y_log10()  +  coord_flip()
``` --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-fig1-worldwide-case-counts-in-major-outbreaks-data-sources-who-cdc&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;plot cases&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/plotbarcase_hu10073645641584489576.webp 400w,
               /media/plotbarcase_hu17025792173898046106.webp 760w,
               /media/plotbarcase_hu3169737616762299870.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;//localhost:1313/media/plotbarcase_hu10073645641584489576.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;543&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Fig.1: Worldwide Case Counts in Major Outbreaks. Data sources: WHO, CDC
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;death-counts-tell-a-different-story&#34;&gt;Death Counts Tell a Different Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total deaths due to the outbreaks are shown in Fig. 2. Here I dropped the log scale to show the dramatic differences among the past and ongoing outbreaks. For example, the SARS outbreak from a coronavirus, disappears as a significant cause of worldwide mortality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- ```
{r plotbardeath, include=TRUE, echo=FALSE}

deaths &lt;- c(1648596,163000,11323,774)
outbreak &lt;- c(&#34;COVID-19 (2019)&#34;, &#34;H1N1 (2009)&#34;, &#34;Ebola (2014)&#34;, &#34;SARS (2003)&#34;)

df &lt;- as.data.frame(deaths, outbreak)

theme_set(theme_minimal())

# Plot
g &lt;- ggplot(df, aes(x = reorder(outbreak, deaths), deaths))
g + geom_bar(stat=&#34;identity&#34;, width = 0.7, fill=&#34;coral2&#34;) + 
   geom_text(aes(label=deaths), hjust=-0.1, color=&#34;black&#34;, size=4.0) +
      labs(title=&#34;Fig.2: Worldwide Death Counts in Major Outbreaks&#34;, 
           caption=&#34;Data sources: WHO, CDC Aug 19, 2020&#34;) +
      theme(axis.title.y=element_blank()) + 
  theme(axis.text.y = element_text(size=rel(1.5))) + ylim(0, 2000000) +
  coord_flip()

``` --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-fig2-worldwide-death-counts-in-major-outbreaks-data-sources-who-cdc-aug-19-2020&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;plot deaths&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/plotbardeath_hu17869015885608634849.webp 400w,
               /media/plotbardeath_hu12717155597378379551.webp 760w,
               /media/plotbardeath_hu6711948686741218124.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;//localhost:1313/media/plotbardeath_hu17869015885608634849.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;543&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Fig.2: Worldwide Death Counts in Major Outbreaks. Data sources: WHO, CDC Aug 19, 2020
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data reported during and after an outbreak is likely to include the &lt;em&gt;proportion&lt;/em&gt; of cases or deaths in the population. Sometimes these proportions are called the &amp;ldquo;normalized cases (or deaths).&amp;rdquo; At the simplest level, these proportions are simply the number of cases/deaths divided by the size of the population of concern. Because populations of interest in epidemiology are often large, the ratio is adjusted to the &amp;ldquo;number of cases/deaths per 100,000 in the population.&amp;rdquo; For example, if we found 200 cases in a population of 250,000 people, the normalized cases are:

$$
N^*=\frac{200 \ cases}{250,000 \ people}=0.0008
$$


This mathematical result, while certainly correct, leaves us with trying to imagine a 0.0008 illness. Thus, we can bring the proportion back to the realm of whole people by multiplying the proportion by 100,000:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
$$
n^*=0.0008 \ times \ 100000 = 80\ cases \ per \ 100,000 \ people
$$

&amp;ldquo;Normalizing&amp;rdquo; the case/death counts by population size makes sense for the comparison of the intensity of an outbreak from one administrative boundary to the next. For example, if the administrative boundary is &amp;quot; county&amp;quot; and the example is compared with a second county also having 200 cases of disease but a population size of 1M, then the normalized comparison is 80 versus 20 cases per 100,000. Clearly, the counties that were apparently equal in case counts now are 4-fold different in the normalized case counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;higher-order-measures-in-outbreaks&#34;&gt;Higher Order Measures in Outbreaks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base counts are seldom sufficient for making comparisons among outbreaks and pandemics. For example, if we look at only total case counts, then we have only a cumulative counting measure that begins at the index (first) case and ends some period of time later when no new cases are observed. But the rate of accumulation of new cases might be more relevant to public health planning because it informs the rate at which health services will be needed for case management. There are several higher order or &lt;em&gt;derived&lt;/em&gt; measures of an outbreak that are more useful for understanding not only the population disease process itself, but also the possible demand on health care resources. Such derived measures include, among others:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;incidence (incidence rate; incidence proportion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prevalence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;person-years at risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;case fatality ratio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;infectivity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;virulence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modes of transmission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short blog is not suited for carefully defining all of these terms and then using them to compare outbreaks. I recommend online sources including basic epidemiology text published by CDC.^[&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/csels/dsepd/ss1978/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Principles of Epidemiology in Public Health Practice, Third edition&lt;/a&gt;] We will continue our simplified comparison of outbreaks with only a few key measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparing-the-case-fatality-ratios&#34;&gt;Comparing the case fatality ratios&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/csels/dsepd/ss1978/lesson3/section3.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;case fatality proportion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (also called the case fatality &lt;em&gt;ratio&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;rate&lt;/em&gt;) is a basic measure of great importance in infectious disease epidemiology. The measure gets right to the point of, &amp;ldquo;how lethal is this disease?&amp;rdquo; It is typically defined as the number of cases of a disease that end in death from a specific cause divided by the total number of cases of that disease in a defined population. This endpoint is used colloquially to express the risk of death, &lt;em&gt;given that the individual has the disease&lt;/em&gt;. In other words, what percentage of true cases are expected to die? Using the case fatality ratio (CFR) is where the comparisons of the major outbreaks is turned on its head: now, the relatively low risk of having Ebola virus disease (EVD) looks much worse because, given the patient has EVD, the likelihood of death is about 40% By comparison, the relative chance of death, given an H1N1 infection is 400 times less than the risk of death from EVD. We will visit more characteristic of case fatality ratios in a later post; but for now, look at Fig. 3 for the remarkable differences among the CFRs the pandemics in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- ```
{r uscases, echo=FALSE}
casefatality &lt;- c(2.2,0.1,39.53,9.56)

outbreak &lt;- c(&#34;COVID-19 (2019)&#34;, &#34;H1N1 (2009)&#34;, &#34;Ebola (2014)&#34;, &#34;SARS (2003)&#34;)

df &lt;- as.data.frame(casefatality, outbreak)

theme_set(theme_minimal())

# Plot
g &lt;- ggplot(df, aes(x = reorder(outbreak, casefatality), casefatality))
g + geom_bar(stat=&#34;identity&#34;, width = 0.7, fill=&#34;chartreuse4&#34;) + 
   geom_text(aes(label=casefatality), hjust=1.6, color=&#34;white&#34;, size=4.0) +
      labs(title=&#34;Fig.3: Case Fatality Ratios (%) in Major Outbreaks&#34;, 
           caption=&#34;Data sources: WHO, CDC&#34;) +
      theme(axis.title.y=element_blank() ) + 
      theme(axis.text.y = element_text(size=rel(1.5))) +
      coord_flip()
      
``` --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-fig-3-case-fatality-ratios--in-major-outbreaks-data-sources-who-cdc&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;The case fatality ratios&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/uscases_hu5177947395891799217.webp 400w,
               /media/uscases_hu5710196219568358464.webp 760w,
               /media/uscases_hu17791834305310666828.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;//localhost:1313/media/uscases_hu5177947395891799217.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;543&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Fig. 3: Case Fatality Ratios (%) in Major Outbreaks. Data sources: WHO, CDC
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-comparisons&#34;&gt;Other Comparisons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;infectivity-and-modes-of-transmission&#34;&gt;Infectivity and Modes of Transmission&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infectivity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Viral infectivity&lt;/a&gt; is the ability of a pathogen to establish infection. Virulence is a measure that is really at the interface between the environment&amp;ndash;air, water, other fluids and solid surfaces&amp;ndash;and the host. In other words, if the viral particles are in the air that the host breathes, what is the likelihood that the host will be infected? Viral infectivity is correlated (positive) with the virulence of the virus. Although we might attempt to compare the infectivity of the three outbreaks in the abstract, in fact, the modes of transmission are different, complicating a simple comparison. The coronavirus causing SARS and COVID-19 are clearly transmitted primarily by inhalation of contaminated air, whereas the infection by Ebola virus is through contact with bodily fluids, tissues and contaminated surfaces from an EVD patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;derived-measures&#34;&gt;Derived measures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prevalence&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;incidence&lt;/em&gt; are two classical epidemiology measurements that are derived from the number of cases or deaths. The first of these&amp;ndash;prevalence&amp;ndash; is the proportion of cases in a defined population at a fixed time point. The &amp;ldquo;defined population&amp;rdquo; is central to both the epidemiology of a single outbreak and the comparison of different outbreaks and from possibly different viruses. Defined population can be based on administrative boundaries, e.g., the population within a county, state, country or continent; or, the definition might be a specific age group with other characteristics. The wide range of possible definition makes prevalence-based a potential minefield of errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incidence or &lt;em&gt;incidence rate&lt;/em&gt; of disease is also difficult to use in comparisons across types of outbreaks. Incidence refers to the number of new cases in a defined population of susceptible hosts over a set period of time (e.g., &amp;ldquo;per year&amp;rdquo;). Incidence rates suffer from the same challenges of the related prevalence of disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;outbreak-measures-can-and-do-change&#34;&gt;Outbreak measures can and do change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it might appear that the fundamental measurements in epidemiology, cases and deaths, can be easily tallied, in fact the &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; number of cases/deaths in an outbreak can be difficult to obtain and might not even be known for several years after the outbreak!^[For example, the total cases in the H1N1 influenza (2009) cases are still uncertain a decade after the outbreak.] This happens because the signs and symptoms for many infectious diseases are overlapping, and might even overlap with those of the infected person&amp;rsquo;s pre-existing conditions. If there is no way to clearly identify the infectious agent, then the clinician diagnoses the disease by comparing with a current knowledge base of signs and symptoms.  With a novel disease like COVID-19, the scientific and regulatory communities will debate the exact definition of a COVID-19 case in the midst of the pandemic because the &amp;ldquo;recognized&amp;rdquo; signs and symptoms are likely to change with more experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I have shown that just a few simplistic comparisons using basic epidemiologic measures can easily dispel the notion that the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic is &amp;ldquo;just like the annual flu.&amp;rdquo; A deeper dive into the specifics of infectivity, virulence, age-dependency and co-morbidities would take volumes to discuss in even moderate depth. More importantly, the knowledge base on COVID-19 is rapidly evolving due to the efforts of scientists and public health officials to gather and share data. As Dr. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.niaid.nih.gov/about/director&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Anthony Fauci&lt;/a&gt; remarked recently, understanding the long-term effects of COVID-19 is a &amp;ldquo;work in progress.&amp;quot;^[&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnn.com/world/live-news/coronavirus-pandemic-08-19-20-intl/h_24a802929c742bc3facdb547684b2645&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CNN&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Counties Covid-19 Tracking Website</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/covid-counties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/covid-counties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Google Sites website for tracking Covid-19 statisics for counties in which I have family&amp;ndash;close or distant. The site is dormant as the US and university data source have suspended operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Subjectivity in Risk Decision-Making: The Benefits of Multicriteria Decision Analysis</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2018-controlling-subjectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2018-controlling-subjectivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prince of Peace Lutheran Church (Website)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/website-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/website-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A WordPress (.org) website created for Prince of Peace Lutheran Church.
The site archives sermon notes, provides church event calendars and newletters and links to newsletters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example journal article</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/journal-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/journal-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the publication&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;full text&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;supplementary notes&lt;/strong&gt; here. You can use rich formatting such as including &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Systematic Approach of Employing Quality by Design Principles: Risk Assessment and Design of Experiments to Demonstrate Process Understanding and Identify the Critical Process Parameters for Coating of the Ethylcellulose Pseudolatex Dispersion Using Non-Conventional Fluid Bed Process</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2014-systematic-approach-empolying-qbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2014-systematic-approach-empolying-qbd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality-by-Design III: Application of Near-Infrared Spectroscopy to Monitor Roller Compaction In-process and Product Quality Attributes of Immediate Release Tablets</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2018-quality-by-design-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2018-quality-by-design-iii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example conference paper</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/conference-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/conference-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the publication&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;full text&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;supplementary notes&lt;/strong&gt; here. You can use rich formatting such as including &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The reliability-quality relationship for quality systems and quality risk management</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2012-reliability-quality-relationship-qrm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 14:01:07 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2012-reliability-quality-relationship-qrm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability Concepts in Quality Risk Management</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2011-probability-concepts-in-qrm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2011-probability-concepts-in-qrm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspective on Quality Risk Management of Pharmaceutical Quality</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2007-perspective-on-qrm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2007-perspective-on-qrm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📈 Communicate your results effectively with the best data visualizations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/data-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/data-visualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wowchemy is designed to give technical content creators a seamless experience. You can focus on the content and Wowchemy handles the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use popular tools such as Plotly, Mermaid, and data frames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charts&#34;&gt;Charts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wowchemy supports the popular &lt;a href=&#34;https://plot.ly/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Plotly&lt;/a&gt; format for interactive data visualizations. With Plotly, you can design almost any kind of visualization you can imagine!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save your Plotly JSON in your page folder, for example &lt;code&gt;line-chart.json&lt;/code&gt;, and then add the &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; chart data=&amp;quot;line-chart&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; shortcode where you would like the chart to appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demo:&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;div id=&#34;chart-137246895&#34; class=&#34;chart&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  async function fetchChartJSON() {
    console.debug(&#39;Hugo Blox fetching chart JSON...&#39;)
    const response = await fetch(&#39;.\/line-chart.json&#39;);
    return await response.json();
  }

  (function() {
    let a = setInterval( function() {
      if ( typeof window.Plotly === &#39;undefined&#39; ) {
        console.debug(&#39;Plotly not loaded yet...&#39;)
        return;
      }
      clearInterval( a );

      fetchChartJSON().then(chart =&gt; {
        console.debug(&#39;Plotting chart...&#39;)
        window.Plotly.newPlot(&#39;chart-137246895&#39;, chart.data, chart.layout, {responsive: true});
      });
    }, 500 );
  })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might also find the &lt;a href=&#34;http://plotly-json-editor.getforge.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Plotly JSON Editor&lt;/a&gt; useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;diagrams&#34;&gt;Diagrams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wowchemy supports the &lt;em&gt;Mermaid&lt;/em&gt; Markdown extension for diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;flowchart&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;```mermaid
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;graph TD
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;A[Hard] --&amp;gt;|Text| B(Round)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;B --&amp;gt; C{Decision}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;C --&amp;gt;|One| D[Result 1]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;C --&amp;gt;|Two| E[Result 2]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;```
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mermaid&#34;&gt;graph TD
A[Hard] --&gt;|Text| B(Round)
B --&gt; C{Decision}
C --&gt;|One| D[Result 1]
C --&gt;|Two| E[Result 2]
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;sequence diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;```mermaid
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;sequenceDiagram
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Alice-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Hello John, how are you?
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;loop Healthcheck
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    John-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Fight against hypochondria
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;end
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Note right of John: Rational thoughts!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;John--&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Alice: Great!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;John-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Bob: How about you?
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Bob--&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Jolly good!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;```
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mermaid&#34;&gt;sequenceDiagram
Alice-&gt;&gt;John: Hello John, how are you?
loop Healthcheck
    John-&gt;&gt;John: Fight against hypochondria
end
Note right of John: Rational thoughts!
John--&gt;&gt;Alice: Great!
John-&gt;&gt;Bob: How about you?
Bob--&gt;&gt;John: Jolly good!
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;class diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;```mermaid
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;classDiagram
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class01 &amp;lt;|-- AveryLongClass : Cool
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class03 *-- Class04
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class05 o-- Class06
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class07 .. Class08
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class09 --&amp;gt; C2 : Where am i?
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class09 --* C3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class09 --|&amp;gt; Class07
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class07 : equals()
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class07 : Object[] elementData
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class01 : size()
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class01 : int chimp
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class01 : int gorilla
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class08 &amp;lt;--&amp;gt; C2: Cool label
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;```
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mermaid&#34;&gt;classDiagram
Class01 &lt;|-- AveryLongClass : Cool
Class03 *-- Class04
Class05 o-- Class06
Class07 .. Class08
Class09 --&gt; C2 : Where am i?
Class09 --* C3
Class09 --|&gt; Class07
Class07 : equals()
Class07 : Object[] elementData
Class01 : size()
Class01 : int chimp
Class01 : int gorilla
Class08 &lt;--&gt; C2: Cool label
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;state diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;```mermaid
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;stateDiagram
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;[*] --&amp;gt; Still
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Still --&amp;gt; [*]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Still --&amp;gt; Moving
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Moving --&amp;gt; Still
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Moving --&amp;gt; Crash
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Crash --&amp;gt; [*]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;```
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mermaid&#34;&gt;stateDiagram
[*] --&gt; Still
Still --&gt; [*]
Still --&gt; Moving
Moving --&gt; Still
Moving --&gt; Crash
Crash --&gt; [*]
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-frames&#34;&gt;Data Frames&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save your spreadsheet as a CSV file in your page&amp;rsquo;s folder and then render it by adding the &lt;em&gt;Table&lt;/em&gt; shortcode to your page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34; data-lang=&#34;go&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;table&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;results.csv&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;header&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;true&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;caption&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Table 1: My results&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;table class=&#34;table-auto w-full&#34;&gt;
  
    
    
    &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;  &lt;th class=&#34;border-b dark:border-slate-600 font-medium p-4 pt-0 pb-3 text-slate-400 dark:text-slate-200 text-left&#34;&gt;customer_id&lt;/th&gt;  &lt;th class=&#34;border-b dark:border-slate-600 font-medium p-4 pt-0 pb-3 text-slate-400 dark:text-slate-200 text-left&#34;&gt;score&lt;/th&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/thead&gt;
  
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  
    &lt;tr&gt;
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;number&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;number&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  
    &lt;tr&gt;
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;number&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;text&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;0.5&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  
    &lt;tr&gt;
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;number&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;number&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  
    &lt;caption class=&#34;table-caption&#34;&gt;Table 1: My results&lt;/caption&gt;
  
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-helpful-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page helpful? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>👩🏼‍🏫 Teach academic courses</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/teach-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/teach-courses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hugoblox.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo Blox Builder&lt;/a&gt; is designed to give technical content creators a seamless experience. You can focus on the content and the Hugo Blox Builder which this template is built upon handles the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed videos, podcasts, code, LaTeX math, and even test students!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this page, you&amp;rsquo;ll find some examples of the types of technical content that can be rendered with Hugo Blox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teach your course by sharing videos with your students. Choose from one of the following approaches:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D2vj0WcvH5c?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; youtube w7Ft2ymGmfc &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bilibili&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; bilibili id=&amp;quot;BV1WV4y1r7DF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos may be added to a page by either placing them in your &lt;code&gt;assets/media/&lt;/code&gt; media library or in your &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/page-bundles/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&amp;rsquo;s folder&lt;/a&gt;, and then embedding them with the &lt;em&gt;video&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; video src=&amp;quot;my_video.mp4&amp;quot; controls=&amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add a podcast or music to a page by placing the MP3 file in the page&amp;rsquo;s folder or the media library folder and then embedding the audio on your page with the &lt;em&gt;audio&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; audio src=&amp;quot;ambient-piano.mp3&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try it out:&lt;/p&gt;








  








&lt;audio controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/teach-courses/ambient-piano.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-students&#34;&gt;Test students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide a simple yet fun self-assessment by revealing the solutions to challenges with the &lt;code&gt;spoiler&lt;/code&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;spoiler&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;👉 Click to view the solution&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;You found me!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;spoiler&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;cursor-pointer&#34;&gt;👉 Click to view the solution&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;rounded-lg bg-neutral-50 dark:bg-neutral-800 p-2&#34;&gt;
    You found me 🎉
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder supports a Markdown extension for $\LaTeX$ math. You can enable this feature by toggling the &lt;code&gt;math&lt;/code&gt; option in your &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To render &lt;em&gt;inline&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;block&lt;/em&gt; math, wrap your LaTeX math with &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$...${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$$...$${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;We wrap the LaTeX math in the Hugo Blox &lt;em&gt;math&lt;/em&gt; shortcode to prevent Hugo rendering our math as Markdown.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;math block&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\gamma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\frac&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^T &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; |}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;

$$\gamma_{n} = \frac{ \left | \left (\mathbf x_{n} - \mathbf x_{n-1} \right )^T \left [\nabla F (\mathbf x_{n}) - \nabla F (\mathbf x_{n-1}) \right ] \right |}{\left \|\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n}) - \nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n-1}) \right \|^2}$$


&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;inline math&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; renders as $\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})$
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;multi-line math&lt;/strong&gt; using the math linebreak (&lt;code&gt;\\&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;k;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\begin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;


$$
f(k;p_{0}^{*}) = \begin{cases}p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=1, \\
1-p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=0.\end{cases}
$$



&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder utilises Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Markdown extension for highlighting code syntax. The code theme can be selected in the &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```python
import pandas as pd
data = pd.read_csv(&amp;quot;data.csv&amp;quot;)
data.head()
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pandas&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;read_csv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;data.csv&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;inline-images&#34;&gt;Inline Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34; data-lang=&#34;go&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;icon&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;python&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;}}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;inline-block  pr-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;svg style=&#34;height: 1em; transform: translateY(0.1em);&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; height=&#34;1em&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 448 512&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M439.8 200.5c-7.7-30.9-22.3-54.2-53.4-54.2h-40.1v47.4c0 36.8-31.2 67.8-66.8 67.8H172.7c-29.2 0-53.4 25-53.4 54.3v101.8c0 29 25.2 46 53.4 54.3 33.8 9.9 66.3 11.7 106.8 0 26.9-7.8 53.4-23.5 53.4-54.3v-40.7H226.2v-13.6h160.2c31.1 0 42.6-21.7 53.4-54.2 11.2-33.5 10.7-65.7 0-108.6zM286.2 404c11.1 0 20.1 9.1 20.1 20.3 0 11.3-9 20.4-20.1 20.4-11 0-20.1-9.2-20.1-20.4.1-11.3 9.1-20.3 20.1-20.3zM167.8 248.1h106.8c29.7 0 53.4-24.5 53.4-54.3V91.9c0-29-24.4-50.7-53.4-55.6-35.8-5.9-74.7-5.6-106.8.1-45.2 8-53.4 24.7-53.4 55.6v40.7h106.9v13.6h-147c-31.1 0-58.3 18.7-66.8 54.2-9.8 40.7-10.2 66.1 0 108.6 7.6 31.6 25.7 54.2 56.8 54.2H101v-48.8c0-35.3 30.5-66.4 66.8-66.4zm-6.7-142.6c-11.1 0-20.1-9.1-20.1-20.3.1-11.3 9-20.4 20.1-20.4 11 0 20.1 9.2 20.1 20.4s-9 20.3-20.1 20.3z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt; Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-helpful-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page helpful? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phenol sensitization of DNA to subsequent oxidative damage in 8-hydroxyguanine assays</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/1992-8ohdg-phenol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 1992 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/1992-8ohdg-phenol/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The risk of trusting priority numbers</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2017-risk-of-trusting-priority-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:37 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2017-risk-of-trusting-priority-numbers/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality-by-Design II: Application of Quantitative Risk Analysis to the Formulation of Ciprofloxacin Tablets</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2016-quality-by-design-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:34 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2016-quality-by-design-ii/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality by design I: application of failure mode effect analysis (FMEA) and Plackett-Burman design of experiments in the identification of “main factors” in the formulation and process design space for roller-compacted ciprofloxacin hydrochloride immediate-release tablets.</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2013-quality-by-design-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:32 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2013-quality-by-design-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk, uncertainty, and process analytical technology</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2006-risk-pat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:26 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2006-risk-pat/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elicitation of expert knowledge about risks associated with pharmaceutical manufacturing processes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2005-elicitation-expert-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2005-elicitation-expert-knowledge/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antimicrobial Resistance Risk Assessment in Food Safety</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2004-arra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2004-arra/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embed a Power Point</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/new-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/new-show/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using the spoiler&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;cursor-pointer&#34;&gt;This element can be toggled&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;rounded-lg bg-neutral-50 dark:bg-neutral-800 p-2&#34;&gt;
    TOGGLE
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;show-button onclick=&#34;toggleElement(&#39;myElement&#39;)&#34;&gt;Toggle&lt;/show-button&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;myElement&#34;&gt;This element can be toggled.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&#34;favorite styled&#34; type=&#34;button&#34;&gt;Add to favorites&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
[My Power Point](https://onedrive.live.com/edit.aspx?resid=B16B51D1F70656AA!72448&amp;cid=b16b51d1f70656aa&amp;CT=1736194665593&amp;OR=ItemsView) --&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=B16B51D1F70656AA%2172448&amp;amp;authkey=%21AEBaaUG2kDJMkwA&amp;amp;em=2&amp;amp;wdAr=1.7777777777777777&#34; width=&#34;476px&#34; height=&#34;288px&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;This is an embedded &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://office.com&#34;&gt;Microsoft Office&lt;/a&gt; presentation, powered by &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://office.com/webapps&#34;&gt;Office&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
